Last week, we worked with models that were able to speed up code by a factor of 60,000 times, which
지난주에는 코드를 60,000배나 빠르게 만드는 모델로 작업했는데 정말
was outrageous.
굉장했죠
Hopefully you were super impressed by that, because I certainly was, and I'm hoping you're going to
깊은 인상을 받았길 바라요 저도 그랬거든요 이번 주말에는
be even more impressed at the end of this week when you see what I have in store for you.
더 깊은 인상을 받길 바라요 제가 준비한 걸 보면요
So it's all about rag retrieval.
걸레 회수 작업이군요
Augmented generation, where you can already do, of course, is code with frontier models, code with
이미 가능한 증강세대 기술은 개척자 모델이나 얼굴 트랜스포머를 껴안는
hugging face transformers.
코드였죠
Choose the right LLM for your project and now build solutions that generate code.
프로젝트에 맞는 LLM을 선택하고 코드를 생성하는 솔루션을 빌드하세요
Today you're going to learn about the big idea behind Rag retrieval augmented generation.
오늘은 걸레 회수 증강세대의 원대한 아이디어에 대해 배울 거예요
And we're going to walk through some of the interactions with Rag before we get there though, we're
그 전에 Rag와의 상호 작용을 살펴볼 거예요 그리고 Rag에 숨은
also going to talk about the little idea, the small idea behind rag, which is actually quite obvious.
작은 아이디어에 대해서도 얘기할 겁니다 사실 꽤 명백하죠
In fact, you may have already thought about it yourself.
사실 이미 생각해 두셨을 수도 있죠
And then we're going to implement a toy version of Rag using the small idea.
그런 다음 작은 아이디어를 이용해 래그의 장난감 버전을 구현할 거예요
So you get a really good feel for how it works.
어떻게 작동하는지 감이 잘 와요 Get it
Before next week, we go on to the real deal.
다음 주 전에 진짜 일을 할 거예요
Let me start by giving you some of the intuition behind rag.
우선 누더기에 대한 직감부터 말씀드릴게요
We've already seen that we can make the performance of models stronger by enriching the prompts, the
모델에 보내는 정보인 프롬프트를 강화함으로써 모델의 성능을 강화할 수 있다는
information that we send to the models.
건 이미 확인했죠
And we've done that in several ways.
여러 가지 방법으로 그렇게 했어요
We've used Multi-shot prompting to send a series of example questions and answers to the model.
멀티샷 프롬프팅을 이용해 모델에 일련의 질문과 답을 예로 보냈는데요
We've used tools so that the LLM can call back into our code almost kind of, and run some code that
도구를 사용해 LLM이 우리 코드로 다시 호출해 응답을 보충하거나 작업을 수행하는
then is used to supplement its answers or carry out actions.
데 사용되는 코드를 실행했어요
And we've had other ways to provide additional context as part of what we send the LLM, including in
LLM에 보내는 것의 일부로 추가적인 컨텍스트를 제공하는 다른 방법도 있었습니다 시스템 프롬프트를
the system prompt.
포함해서요
So the thinking is, can we step up this idea and take it to a new level by supplying more concrete
그래서 이 아이디어를 새로운 단계로 끌어올릴 수 있을지 고민했죠 프롬프트에 좀 더 구체적인 정보를
information into the prompt?
제공하면서요
That's going to be particularly relevant to the question at hand.
현재 당면한 문제와 특히 관련이 있죠
So the idea is could we put together a database of information sometimes because this is a database
그래서 때로는 정보 데이터베이스를 만들기도 합니다. 왜냐하면 이건 지식 데이터베이스니까요.
of knowledge, it's known as a knowledge base, a knowledge base of information.
지식 기반으로 알려져 있죠. 지식 기반이요.
And every time that the user asks us a question, we'll first look up in that knowledge base whether
사용자가 질문을 할 때마다 그 지식 기반에서 먼저 살펴봅니다 우리가
there's any relevant information that we can pluck out.
빼낼 수 있는 관련 정보가 있는지요
And if there is, we simply stuff that in the prompt and that is sent in the prompt to the model.
있다면 프롬프트에 입력하면 됩니다 모델에 프롬프트로 전송되죠
That's all there is to it.
그게 다예요
It's actually a very simple idea, and you probably already thought of it yourself while we were doing
사실 아주 간단한 아이디어입니다 아마 여러분도 이미 생각해두셨겠죠
some of the earlier exercises.
아까 연습할 때요
So let's just show this small idea behind rag in a diagram, and I promise you later we'll get to the
그럼 다이어그램에서 get 뒤에 있는 작은 아이디어를 보여드리죠 나중에 더 큰 아이디어로
bigger idea, which is where it becomes somewhat less less obvious and more meaningful.
갈 거라고 약속드립니다 덜 명확해지고 더 의미 있어지는 거죠
But in the little idea, what we're saying is let's start by the user asking us a question.
하지만 여기서 우리가 하려는 말은 사용자가 질문을 하는 것부터 시작하자는 거죠
It comes to our code, and normally we'd send that straight on to the LLM.
코드로 오면 보통은 그걸 바로 LLM으로 보내죠
But this time before we do so, we do a query in our knowledge base to see if we've got any relevant
하지만 그 전에 기술 기반에서 관련 배경 정보가 있는지 쿼리를
background information.
해요
And if we do, we pluck out that information and we include it in the prompt.
그런 경우 해당 정보를 추출해 프롬프트에 포함시키죠
We send the LM and of course the response comes back as always, but hopefully it takes into account
LM을 보내면 당연히 응답이 돌아오죠 늘 그렇듯이요 하지만 이 추가 컨텍스트를
some of this extra context.
고려하면 좋겠네요
And that is what goes back to the user.
그게 사용자에게 돌아가는 거죠
That's really all there is to the small idea behind Rag.
랙에 담긴 아이디어는 그게 다예요
So we're now going to put this into action with a small example of the small idea.
이제 작은 아이디어의 작은 예로 이걸 작동시켜 볼게요.
Let's say we work for an insurance tech startup.
보험 기술 신생 기업에서 일한다고 가정해 보죠
And it's going to be a fictional insurance tech startup called insurance, which happens to be the word
가짜 기술 회사인 보험 신생 기업이 될 거예요 보험이란 단어가 인보어죠
And LM stuffed together, which is, I think, the limit of my creativity.
LM을 한데 뭉쳐서요 그게 제 창의력의 한계죠
We have a knowledge base in the form of a folder taken from the company's shared drive.
폴더 형태의 지식 기반은 회사의 공유 드라이브에서 가져온 거죠
It is the entire contents of their shared drive, and our task is to build an AI knowledge worker.
공유 드라이브의 전체 콘텐츠죠 인공지능 지식 작업자를 만드는 게 우리 작업이에요
Sometimes this expression knowledge worker is used to mean a person that works for a firm and is the
지식 노동자라는 표현은 때때로 회사에서 일하는 사람을
expert and able to carry out analysis on information about the company and carry out questions and answers.
뜻하기도 합니다 전문가로서 회사의 정보를 분석하고 질문과 답을 수행하는 사람이죠
Well, that's something that we can do with with with an LLM.
LLM으로 할 수 있는 거죠
And we can supplement it with information from the knowledge base.
지식 기반의 정보로 보충할 수 있어요
So we're going to do a toy implementation blunt instrument.
장난감 구현을 해볼게요 둔기요
Um, basically we're going to read in some of these files, products and employees.
기본적으로 이 파일들을 읽어볼 거예요 제품과 직원들
And we're going to store it in like a dictionary.
사전처럼 저장할 거예요
And then anytime a question comes in, we're just going to look up whether or not the word, the name
질문이 들어올 때마다 해당 단어나 직원의 이름이 질문 어딘가에
of the employee appears somewhere in the question.
나오는지를 찾아보죠
And if so, we're just going to shove that whole employee record into our prompt.
만약 그렇다면 전체 직원 기록을 프롬프트에 밀어넣을 거예요
So it's a kind of manual, brute force implementation of Rag, but it will give you a good sense of
일종의 매뉴얼, 무식한 Rag 구현이죠 막후에서 어떻게 작동하는지
how this actually works behind the scenes.
좋은 감각을 제공해요
And it will show you that there's there's no magic to it.
마술이 없다는 걸 보여줄 거예요
It just improves the performance of the model right away.
모델의 성능을 즉시 향상시켜주죠
And then once we've done that, we'll get on to the more exciting stuff.
Get 절차가 끝나면 더 신나는 걸 할 거예요
But for now, let's go to JupyterLab and build our own homemade rag.
하지만 지금은 주피터랩에 가서 직접 천을 만들어 보죠